♪ ♪
( waves lapping )
( birds hooting gently )
♪ ♪
( gasps softly )
( objects clattering in other room )
( drawer closes )
Aunty , do you need anything ?
No , no .
- Just your share for the month . - Yeah , soon I 'll have it .
How is it ?
I start tomorrow , uh ...
Um , uh , the mother Amy , she 's nice .
I pray for you , eh ?
Just work hard to keep it .
Jobs like this , they don 't fall from the sky .
Yes .
- Have a good night . - ( sighs )
Bonsoir , chérie .
( door closes )
( horn honks )
Aisha .
Mm-hmm .
New nanny for the Havs , right ?
Yes .
First elevator on the right .
( elevator chiming )
- Aisha . - Hello , Amy .
( both laugh )
- Welcome . - Thank you .
- How was the commute ? - Yes , good .
- Not too bad . It was okay . - Yeah ? Great .
- ( both chuckle ) - ( cell phone dings )
- Thank you . - ( Aisha chuckles )
How are you ?
I 'm ... I 'm well .
But I think Rose is a little better . She 's very excited .
- Oh , I am , too . I 'm very excited . - ( chuckles )
( Amy laughs )
- Well , um , these are for you . - ( keys jingling )
Oh . Okay .
And I guess , now that it 's official , I 'll give you the full tour ?
- Yes . - Excellent .
Okay . Follow me .
First up is Adam 's office .
We civilians aren 't allowed .
- AISHA : Oh . - ( laughs )
AMY : And this ...
is yours .
I mean , it 's nothing fancy .
Uh , for overnights .
And please , uh , make this space yours .
Bring whatever you need to feel at home : pictures , books , favorite pillow .
Just one small request .
Uh , no candles or incense .
Rose is hypersensitive to certain smells .
Okay .
- AMY : Rose , we 're coming in . - ( knocking )
Honey .
Aisha 's here .
Hi , Aisha .
( speaks French )
I want you to be a good girl for Mommy .
Okay .
AMY : So , uh , please ,
I don 't want you to feel overwhelmed .
Think of it as a loose guide .
A basic schedule , list of where things are .
- Okay . - Any number you could possibly need .
Including her therapist .
And , um , some blank pages for you at the end to make your own .
Okay .
Is this , uh ... is this weird ?
- No . - Okay .
Um ...
I mean , it might be a little bumpy at the beginning , but we will ...
we 'll catch our stride .
Yes , I 'm sure .
May I ...
- Oh , of course . Of course . - ( Amy chuckles )
( sighs ) Thank you .
- AISHA : Mm-hmm . - Thank you .
Thank you .
( chuckles softly )
( elevator chiming )
( whispers ) : Wow .
All right .
Okay .
Can I clean your hands ?
( speaks French )
- Are you hungry ? - Yeah .
Yes . Good . Okay .
This is for you .
You have your spoon .
Bon appétit .
Why are you looking at my food ?
You want to try it ?
Okay .
Take your spoon .
Try just a little bit .
( laughs )
You like it ?
- C 'est bon ? - C 'est bon .
- C 'est délicieux ? - C 'est délicieux .
( laughs ) : Good job , Rose .
Your French is so good .
( Mariatou speaking native language over phone )
( speaks native language ) Lamine . Is he near ?
You know keeping track of your son ...
is like trying to hold water .
Let me get him .
Hi , Mama .
Lamine , my baby .
Are you being a good boy ?
Aunty Mariatou tells me you 're not listening .
- She 's lying . - Ah ? !
You call your aunty a liar ?
I heard you went to Musa 's birthday party .
Was it fun ?
LAMINE : They had so much food .
I ate too much .
There wasn 't anything else that happened ?
Lamine ?
Why did you bite Musa ?
He took my toy .
I don 't want to hear about any more trouble .
When you come here , you will have so many toys .
LAMINE : Okay .
Will it be cold ?
Very cold .
There will be snow on the ground .
Remember the pictures I sent you ?
Looks like white cotton candy .
White cotton candy .
I will have a very warm coat waiting for you .
Lamine ?
Hello ?
I don 't know if you can hear me , but I will see you so soon ,
my love .
( " The Best " by Dr. Sid playing )
♪ She say she want a man ... ♪
( lively chatter , laughter )
WOMAN : Aisha !
- Sallay ! - ( laughing )
You look beautiful .
- Wow . - Look at you .
( both laughing )
As late as I am , they are still setting up ?
My dear , you know our people , now . African time .
( both laughing )
- No stress today . - Hmm .
- Let loose . Have fun , for once . - Yeah . I know .
- Yes , it 's a bracelet . - ( gasping , indistinct chatter )
Aw .
So pretty . You look so nice .
( laughs )
- Are you ready ? - Yes .
- The Salone people know how to party . - ( laughing )
- You know ? You know ? - Let 's go .
You know ?
( song continues )
( jovial chatter , laughter )
- ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪ - ♪ Happy birthday to me ♪
♪ Happy birthday , dear Romano ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you . ♪
( applause , cheering )
♪ ♪
- Cinq . - Cinq .
- Ans . - Ans .
" I am five years old . "
J 'ai cinq ans .
- ( ringtone playing ) - J 'ai cinq ans .
- Hi . - AISHA : Hello . ( chuckles )
Hi . What are you girls up to ?
We are doing French lessons .
Did Rose finish her food ?
Every last drop , yes .
AMY : Thank God .
Picky doesn 't even begin to describe your eating habits , Rose .
So , listen , Adam is coming home earlier than expected ,
so I 'm gonna need all of your help tomorrow getting everything together .
AISHA : Okay .
I 'm very excited for you to meet him .
- Okay , yes . Looking forward . ( chuckles ) - AMY : All right .
- I 'll see you ladies soon . - AISHA : Okay .
- Bye . - AMY : Bye-bye .
( phone beeps )
( sighs )
( elevator chiming )
Hey .
Sorry I am late .
Things got crazy .
I promise to text next time .
AISHA : Rose is in bed .
Great . Uh , everything went smooth ? No tantrums ?
No , no , none at all .
She is so relaxed with you .
You kept all the receipts ?
Yes .
They are all here .
You are amazing . ( chuckles )
Uh , one small thing .
I was wondering if you could do an overnight tomorrow .
I know we didn 't discuss Friday nights , but I have a feeling
things might go a little late , and I 'd like you to keep an eye on Rose .
We agreed on , uh , 100 for the overnight rate , right ?
No , it was , um ... it was 150 .
Oh . Okay . 150 .
Okay .
( chuckles ) : Okay . Good night , Amy .
All right , have a good night .
- Okay . You , too . Thank you . - All right .
Hey , no . Lamine .
Hi , Mommy .
Sing " Ayo Nene . "
Mama is in the computer .
( Aisha chuckles softly )
Okay , okay , okay , okay , wait , wait .
Come on . Say bye-bye . Say bye-bye .
Bye .
( singing " Ayo Nene " in native language )
( siren wailing in distance )
♪ ♪
Sir , you can put the wine here .
And , um , you can leave that there .
Thank you .
( shower running )
Rose ?
( singsongy ) : I 'm coming to get you .
Rose .
( Rose giggling nearby )
AISHA : I wonder where she is .
( gasps , laughs )
- You found me ! - I did !
I found you .
You were under the bed .
Oh , so smart .
Okay , ladies and gentlemen .
- In our left corner , we have Rose . - Here .
And in our right corner , we have the reigning champion ,
Madame Rainbow .
One , and two , and three !
Let 's go !
( Aisha making punching noises )
( both squeal , laugh )
AISHA : Oh , Rose is down for the count .
You beat me . I have lost my title .
You two are having fun .
( laughs ) Go to Mommy .
I 'm tired .
Oh . Too much play . ( laughs )
- ( chuckles ) I can see that . - ( Aisha laughs )
You 're tired , huh ?
Hmm ?
Don 't go far .
♪ ♪
( vacuum whirring )
AMY : Thank you for picking up the dry cleaning .
I didn 't think to bring anything fancy .
Oh , gosh . It 's my fault .
I should 've told you .
It 's just that my head is in a million different places with work and ...
You know .
( cell phone dings )
But it 's fine .
Oh , wait . You know what ?
( sighs )
Oh , my ...
I swear this dress was made for your skin .
- ( chuckles ) - I mean , geez .
Mahogany red . Yeah .
Imperial red . Wine red .
The whole family . ( laughs )
Okay .
( zipping )
( whispers ) : Wow .
Oh .
It 's very tight .
Oh , it 's ... perfect .
Okay .
( " Waves " by Denitia playing )
( laughing ) : Exactly .
( indistinct chatter , laughter )
At least he thought it .
- In the very least , yes . Thank you . - ( Amy laughing )
( indistinct chatter continues )
( elevator chiming )
( song continues over speakers )
Well , hello there .
Mm , mm .
- Nice to see you . - Hey , hold on .
Hold on . Hey , hey , hey , hey . Stop , stop , stop .
Just let me put my shit down .
( scoffing chuckle )
ADAM : Why are you dressed like that ?
I 'm sorry , but we haven 't even ...
ALL : Surprise !
AMY ( chuckles ) : Surprise .
Daddy !
( grunts ) Hi .
Hey , I got something for you .
( unzips bag )
Wow .
Anansi the Spider .
MAN : Welcome back , Adam .
- Bonjour ! - ADAM ( laughing ) : Hey .
( chatter continues indistinctly in other room )
( music playing softly )
( Aisha exhales )
MAN ( in other room ) : Except that that kind of sounds like PC bullshit .
Seriously , just tell me , how does burning shit down help the cause ?
WOMAN : Are you cool waxing philosophical and being the devil 's advocate ?
Listen , the devil 's got enough help .
You didn 't care about the message
- in the first place . - Tell me , how does ... - Exactly .
- WOMAN 2 : No , no , Richard , it 's fine . - Burning shit down
and-and-and looting stores in your own fucking neighborhood
help the cause ?
This is not a rhetorical question , people .
WOMAN : Okay .
ADAM : Uh , I 'm sorry . You 're gonna have to bear with me a little bit . Um ...
( chatter continues in other room )
Amy and I had talked about hiring someone , but I didn 't know that she had .
It 's lovely to meet you , but it 's a little bit of a surprise .
( drawer opens )
She asked me to pay you for tonight .
Anyway , I think from here on out , she 'll keep track , but ...
- Thank you . - Yeah .
Uh ... ( speaks French )
- Yeah , okay . - ( laughs )
- You can laugh . - It 's not bad .
I was just in , uh ... in Lille , France .
They had an uprising there around police violence .
- Oh . Mm-hmm . - Yeah .
Yeah , that kid , he had a real fire in him .
Maybe the best public speaker I 've ever seen .
He was like Malcolm X.
They hung on his every word .
He 's dead now .
What happened ?
Police said it was gang-related .
- I 'm going to go to bed now . - ( chuckles ) Please , go to sleep .
- Okay . - I wish I could .
- Bonne nuit . - Bonne nuit .
MARIATOU : Lamine . Lamine .
( over video ) : You know it 's a different time in America ?
Now it 's night there .
Before we leave the beach ...
Lamine , tell Mommy bye-bye .
LAMINE : Bye , Mommy .
( waves sloshing on video )
- ( thunder rumbling ) - ( distorted scream )
( gasps )
♪ ♪
( distorted scream )
( doorknob rattles )
( rattles )
( grabs object )
( switch clicks )
( creaking , rattling )
( thumping )
( creaking )
♪ ♪
( gasps )
( panting )
♪ ♪
( " Yeanoh ( Powe 'hande Binga 'dbe ) " by Kondi Band playing )
( song fades )
AISHA : Thank you .
Dakar , Senegal , right ?
Yes .
When will they get it ?
About two business days .
That 's cool ?
Yes . Thanks , Nikki .
How 's your little chocolate drop ?
He 's good .
He 's coming to America , finally .
Yes . I want him to celebrate his birthday with me .
He coming to live or visit ?
To live , thank God .
Word !
African boy coming to the Big Apple . Okay !
- MAN : Let 's go . - NIKKI : All right .
Relax , y 'all . Y 'all ain 't got no job to go to .
Aisha , you all set .
Kiss those cheeks for me , all right ?
AISHA : Bye .
NIKKI : Mm-hmm .
- ( screaming ) - ( man on TV shouts )
I was like , this girl has forgotten about me now .
- No call , no text , no visit . - AISHA : No , no , no .
They own me , Sallay .
- I have no life . - My dear , who are you telling ?
I 've been braiding since last night .
This is my only customer today , and then I 'm going to sleep .
Mm , work until you die .
The American dream , right ? ( laughs )
Sallay , I told you about pulling on my edges .
Sorry , sorry , sorry .
Have you thought about going back ?
- You know , to live . - AISHA : To live ?
Where ? With what money ?
( laughing ) : What are you talking about ?
I know .
Nigeria has definitely seen the last of me .
I 'd rather be asleep in America than asleep in Africa .
At least here , when you work , you see the money .
- AISHA : Mm . - ( Sallay chuckles )
Do we ?
I think maybe if you apologized to Lamine 's father and his wife ,
maybe they can help you .
You know , send you money or something .
Apologize ? For what ?
It is him who should apologize .
For impregnating every teen girl on her way to school .
( scoffs ) He knew he was married when he paid for my school fees .
When he gave me money for food , clothes , my sick mother .
Trust me , I know how it is .
All these big men that play with little girls ,
and it 's always the little girls who are punished .
He doesn 't care whether his own son lives or dies .
He has not met him . You know that ?
Can you imagine ?
Cut me off when I was pregnant .
( sighs )
I remember the night I found out .
I went to the beach .
The moon was so big .
The water was so cold at my feet .
This one I would keep .
Lamine is the best thing that happened to me , Sallay .
He is my greatest work .
( chuckles )
He 's a beautiful boy .
I can 't wait for him to meet you , huh ?
- His new girlfriend . - ( Sallay laughing )
He will love you . I know .
He 's a ladies ' man .
( chuckles )
( Aisha chuckles )
( sighs )
I 've missed you .
I just want you to be happy , Aisha .
You can 't just work from morning till night ,
night till morning .
You need to get out .
AISHA : I 'm okay , Sallay . I 'm fine .
I am .
- I love you . - I love you .
( water running )
( to tune of " Frère Jacques " ) : ♪ Wash your hands , wash your hands ♪
♪ In between , in between ♪
♪ Don 't forget the back , don 't forget the back ♪
♪ And your wrist ♪
BOTH : ♪ And your wrist . ♪
Hmm .
( water runs , stops )
What are you drawing ?
- A unicorn . - A unicorn ?
♪ ♪
( grabs knife )
Rose ? Rose .
( shower running )
Rose ?
♪ ♪
( whispers ) : Mommy 's resting .
Rose , come . Come on .
AISHA : Okay , it 's time to eat now , Rose .
- Hi . - ROSE : Daddy !
Hi , piglet . How are you ?
You ready to go ?
- Yeah . - Yeah ?
- Hi , Aisha . - Hi .
What time do you get off today ?
Um , I 'm not sure . I was going to ask .
Amy 's here , but she 's , um , resting .
You , uh ... you want to come to dinner with us ?
Um , are-are you sure ?
Yeah .
- You want me to come , Rose ? - Good ?
- Okay . - ADAM : Let 's get some shoes on you .
I don 't know what you did to her ,
but she hasn 't eaten this much in months .
- Really ? - It 's nice .
She loves to eat . ( laughs )
Whose child are you talking about ?
- ( both laugh ) - I mean ...
I-I make her some Senegalese food , and she loves it .
Rose , you like the chebu jën , yes ?
- C 'est bon ? C 'est bon ? - C 'est bon .
What did you do before you came here ?
- I was a teacher in Senegal . - Right . Of course you were .
I , um ... I-I studied English and French in school .
You 're a wonderful teacher .
And you 're clearly very smart , Aisha . I know ...
I can tell you 're not gonna be with us for very long .
Much as I 'd like to keep you .
Can I ask you something ?
Sure .
I am having a difficult time with the hours .
Thank you .
I don 't mind working the hours ,
but I think Amy forgets sometimes , um , to pay me .
Um , there are many hours I have not been paid .
About a week 's worth of pay .
I 'm sorry .
I 'll talk to her .
I won 't say you brought it up . I 'll talk to her .
Well , I was wondering if ... if it 's possible
if you could be in charge of my pay since your hours seem more flexible .
Uh , I would like to , but ...
- WOMAN : Adam ? Is that you ? - ( chuckles )
- Oh , my God . Hi . - ADAM : Oh , my God . How are you ?
- ( kisses ) - Hey .
You look amazing .
- It 's nice to see you . - Nice to see you .
- ( gasps ) Hi . - Remember Rose ?
Last time I saw you , you were just a teeny , tiny thing .
- Bonjour . - ( squeals ) Oh , my gosh , how cute !
ADAM : This is Aisha .
Aisha , this is Christie .
Hi .
I 'm gonna pay the bill , but , uh , you guys should go on ahead .
But I will talk to her about that at home .
Okay . Thank you .
Okay , Rose . On y va .
- Hello . - Hi .
So , you following me or what ?
- Do you want me to be following you ? - ( chuckles ) : Oh .
I like how you said that .
( both chuckling )
Uh , so you gonna tell me where you from ?
Or do you think I 'm like every other dumb American
who thinks that Africa is just one big-ass country ?
( Aisha laughing )
Mm , it starts with an " S. "
Starts with an " S. " Okay , starts with an " S. "
♪ Sierra Leone . ♪
- ( chuckles ) No . - No ?
- South Africa . - ( clicks tongue )
Mm . Okay . Okay .
Senegal .
- O ... kay ! - Wow .
- Ah ... - ( Aisha laughing )
We got a winner .
( both laughing )
Yo .
You didn 't think I knew that , huh ?
Yo , but let me ask you this , though .
Who has the best jollof rice ?
- ' Cause let Nigerians tell it , I mean ... - Mm .
Let Nigerians tell it , they have the best of everything .
Oh , let Nigerians tell it , they have the best of ... ? Okay .
What do you know about jollof rice ?
What don 't I know about jollof rice ?
Jollof rice over here , jollof rice over there .
- Jollof rice in that bag . - ( laughing )
Yeah , I know you snuck it in there .
Okay .
Good to see you .
Good night , Miss Aisha .
( chuckles )
( quiet chatter )
( cell phone dings )
( line ringing )
( Mariatou speaking French in recorded voice mail greeting )
( line beeps )
♪ ♪
( women screaming faintly )
( women wailing )
( wailing grows louder )
( women screaming )
( baby wails , cries nearby )
( seabird chirping )
( alarm chiming over cell phone )
( alarm stops )
( sighs )
( elevator chiming )
( door opens )
Bishop .
What did I say are the rules when you come with Daddy to work , hmm ?
Don 't wander the hallway because then Daddy will get fired .
All right , now , we almost out of here , okay ?
Hey .
You all right ? You look like you saw a ghost .
No , no . Just tired .
They let you bring him here ?
Let me ? No .
Shit happens . I brought him .
- My dad has a crush on you . - MALIK : Okay . ( chuckles )
- ( laughs ) - ( chuckles softly )
I mean , he ain 't lying , though .
So , what , you think I can see you ?
I mean outside of here .
I think you could .
Goodbye , Bishop .
AISHA ( recorded ) : Hello . You 've reached Aisha .
I can 't come to the phone , but leave a message
and I will call you back as soon as possible .
Thank you .
- ( line beeps ) - MALIK ( recorded ) : Wow .
See , I can 't believe you got me leaving voice mails .
When you gonna let me take you out finally ?
Come through .
We 'll have a good time .
My grandmother won 't take no for an answer .
KATHLEEN : Tea ?
I 've got hibiscus , ginger , turmeric .
( chuckles )
AISHA : Thank you .
Enjoy .
I feel like I 've met you before .
Very possibly . ( chuckles )
I lived all over West Africa for ten years .
( sighs )
Fell in love with that continent .
I miss my country .
Every day .
The good parts .
Do tell me about the bad parts .
( sighs ) : Hmm .
Ah .
That 's one of my favorites .
It 's an interpretation of Mami Wata .
Some believe that the mermaid lures sexuality ,
money and promises of fertility ,
but they 're very dangerous ,
unpredictable and impermanent .
I feel like I saw her .
Them .
My grandmother believed in magic .
But ...
me , I never did .
Whether you do or not ,
you are magic .
What 's your boy 's name ?
How do you know ?
MALIK : All right .
Sorry , sometimes Grandma like to ask a lot of questions .
Does she ask them of all the women that come through here ?
Only the ones that pique my interest .
But there haven 't been many .
That pique your interest ?
Or it 's time to go .
Mm , I love you , Grams .
Stay out of trouble , all right ?
- Mm , maybe . - Okay . Okay .
AISHA : It was really nice to meet you .
( door opens )
Lamine .
( door closes )
( car door opens )
( laughs )
( " Summertime with You " by Titose playing )
MALIK : So ...
- Hmm ? - Have you done soul food before ?
- Is this soul food ? - This is soul food .
- Wow . No , I haven 't . - No . Okay .
- Uh , so there is one rule . One rule only . - Okay . What 's that ?
- Eat everything . - ( laughs ) Okay .
Thank you .
- That was very good . - Mm-hmm .
( speaks phrase in native language )
( repeats phrase )
( Aisha laughs , corrects Malik 's pronunciation )
It means , uh , it was delicious , it was wonderful .
- Thank you . ( repeats phrase ) - AISHA : Yes .
( both laughing )
- No . - Yes . Okay , look . You have to try this .
I-I 'm so full .
Oh , but this is the best cheesecake on the East Coast .
- So you have to . Please . - Okay .
Come on , just one bite .
- Mm-hmm . Mm ! - Mm .
We got a winner .
Can I ask you something ?
Of course . Ask me anything .
Your grandmother ...
( chuckles )
Ah ... Um ...
Well ...
most people are born with the ability to see .
- Oh , she 's a witch . - ( laughs ) : A witch ?
Nah .
A priestess .
- Like a psychic ? - Like a psychic .
In Senegal , we call ' em ... we call this marabout .
That 's Grams . Marabout . Marabouts .
Uh , we 'll call her , we 'll tell her today , change her business card
from " intuitive consultant " and put " marabout . "
( both laugh )
She 's lovely .
- Yeah . - Mm .
Forget the marabout .
You have a son ?
Yes , I do .
Do you want to see a picture of him ?
I do .
- Yes . Yes . - All right .
What 's his name ?
His name is Lamine .
And what 's that mean ?
It means " chosen one . "
" Chosen one . "
Ooh , the chosen ... Okay .
- I get it now . Yes . - ( Aisha laughing )
Look at this brother .
- And that smile ... what ? - ( Aisha laughs )
He 's beautiful . You know that ?
Thank you .
- He 's coming soon for his birthday . - Mm .
I haven 't seen him in almost a year .
Wow . That is ...
like a lifetime for a child .
Yes , I know .
And you ?
- And me ? - Yes .
You have how many kids ?
Ooh . ( clears throat )
Five .
Five ?
- Four plus Bishop ? - Four plus Bishop .
- And how many mothers ? - Ooh .
Five .
Yeah , I don 't like to double-dip , you know ?
I like to spread it around New York .
One in Brooklyn , one in Harlem , one in Queens .
- Oh , gosh . ( laughs ) - ( Malik laughing )
I had you , though .
- I got you . You believed me for a second , though . - No . No .
- Yeah , you did . I saw that face . - I knew you were lying .
You were like , " Let me get my purse . "
( both laughing )
Nah , man , just my little knucklehead Bishop .
- Just Bishop ? - Just Bishop . I promise .
( chuckles ) Mm .
Well , I try not to judge .
Don 't want people judging me .
- That 's real . - Mm .
I respect it .
Was the woman in the pictures in your house ... is that your mother ?
( inhales deeply )
Yeah . Yeah .
- Uh ... - I 'm sorry .
No .
My mom has been talking to herself ,
laughing at the jokes inside her head since I can remember .
I used to hate when she would come pick me up from school .
Folks used to see her before I did .
Pacing back and forth , banging on the lockers ,
making up people in the hallway .
So I started pumping weights .
You know ?
Dressing fly .
No one would talk shit to me about my schizophrenic ma .
- Is she ... - Dead .
( " Plastic 100 ° C " by Sampha playing )
Mm-hmm .
My mother died when I was 12 .
What happened ?
It was cancer .
MALIK : They say that when you love someone ,
they live forever .
♪ It 's so hot , I 've been melting out here ♪
♪ I 'm made out of plastic out here ♪
♪ You touched down in the base of my fears ♪
♪ Houston , can-can-can you hear ? ♪
♪ I 've been melting , melting down here ♪
- ♪ Houston , can-can-can you hear me now ? ♪ - ( song ends )
( " Water " by Tanerélle playing )
♪ ♪
( song ends )
( playful chatter , laughter )
All right .
You ready ? Yes .
- What do you want to do today ? - Um ...
- Maybe the swings ? - Hi .
- Hi . - Hi , Ella .
You want to go ? Okay , à tout à l heure .
- MARIATOU : Hello , how are you ? - Mari ?
Ah , I am just playing .
( Mariatou speaks native language )
- Leave a message . - ( line beeps )
Why did you change your voice mail message , Mari ?
Please keep Lamine up for me .
I get off late these days .
( indistinct chatter )
- Hi . - Hi , dear .
- AISHA : Hello . - Cynthia .
Florence .
- Aisha . - FLORENCE : Nice to meet you , Aisha .
Yeah , it 's nice to meet you .
( Cynthia and Florence chatting indistinctly , laughing )
WOMAN : Chloe ! Come on , baby .
Time to go . We got to go .
- Shit , Cynthia ! - You watch your mouth , David .
Go on and play now .
You can use the exercise .
No manners .
Parents too busy letting him eat junk .
I try to cook real food , but everything too spicy .
Curry too spicy , salt too spicy , air too spicy .
( laughter )
So , why you make the boy call you by your first name ?
( scoffs )
Well , my baby Elizabeth , she know better .
She not gonna know a thing when she burn up .
You better put sunscreen pon dear Lizzie .
Police will lock you up quick fast if you make them people children sick .
- ( laughs ) - You know them quick to say " abuse . "
FLORENCE : Speaking of abuse , remember that Dominican nanny , Sonia ? Mm ?
CYNTHIA : You heard what happened to Sonia ?
Sonia was sick ... the kind you can 't see .
( voice fading ) : Slit her employers ' child throat from ear to ear ...
( thunder rumbling )
♪ ♪
( distorted laughter )
- ( gasps ) - ( children squealing )
How could you let her out of the park ?
Someone will report you .
You okay ?
AISHA : " ' Hold on , son ,
" ' for if you fall ,
" Death is going to get you , '
" Anansi the spider said to his child .
" However , the boy could not hold on any longer .
" Therefore , he fell .
" Death caught the boy
" and opened the burlap bag .
" ' It is your father I want , not you . '
" Then he placed the child into the burlap bag .
" Another of Anansi 's daughters cried out to her father .
" ' Papa , please , my hands are tired .
I am going to fall . ' "
Is Anansi bad , Aisha ?
AISHA : Hmm .
Do you know the word " filou " ?
Filou ?
- Trickster . - Trickster .
Anansi is this big .
Mm-hmm .
And most of the people who bother Anansi
are as big as you or as big as me or bigger .
Therefore , he uses his intelligence to survive .
Sometimes he is good .
Sometimes he is very bad .
But he is a survivor .
Survivant .
Survivant . Survivor .
Yes .
Are you ready to tell me why you left the park , Rose ?
Anansi told me to .
AISHA : Sorry it 's late .
I just want to hear your voice .
I miss you .
Very soon .
LAMINE : Very soon . Always very soon .
AISHA : It 's true , Lamine .
I love you .
LAMINE : Love you , too , Mommy .
( elevator chiming )
( gasps , exhales )
Aisha .
Why are you still here ?
I told Adam to let you go . Where is he ?
I don 't know where Adam is .
I haven 't seen him .
Right .
Um ...
I got a promotion .
I mean , not a raise yet ,
but , uh , um ...
You happy for me ?
( chuckles softly )
I mean , you know what it 's like , right ?
Being a woman .
Overseeing everything .
Expected to go and get drinks with the guys every Friday night
just to , like , pretend you 're one of them .
But we 'll never be one of the guys , will we ?
' Cause it 's a fucking boys ' club .
( rummaging )
Okay .
Do me a favor . Watch Adam .
Good night .
- ( elevator chiming ) - ( doors squeak open )
( shower running )
( shower stops )
♪ ♪
- ( door creaking ) - WOMAN ( whispers ) : Aisha .
Aunty ?
♪ ♪
( gasps )
( trembling breaths )
Rose ?
Come here . ( grunts )
- What have you been doing ? - Daddy .
It 's her bedtime . I was just going to put you to bed .
You ready for bed , piglet ? Come on .
Go with Aisha .
Oh . Hey .
Before I forget , um ...
Amy 's working late , but I know today 's supposed to be payday , right ?
- Yes . Thank you . - You 're welcome .
- Say , " Bonne nuit , papa . " - Bonne nuit , papa .
ADAM : Bonne nuit , Rosie .
Okay .
( sings " Ayo Nene " in native language )
♪ ♪
- Hi . - Hi .
I was just gonna come find you . You hungry ?
Um , yes .
Good .
How was she today ?
She was fine .
Good .
I got this extra spicy .
Amy hates hot food .
Says it dulls the taste buds .
Adam .
Mm-hmm ?
She has not paid me what I am owed .
The thing is ...
I need to bring my son here .
- Your son ? - Yes .
How old is he ?
He will be seven in a few days .
All right , well , I 'll tell you what .
I will , uh ...
I 'll advance you some of the money till we can figure this out .
I 'm sorry , things have been a ...
little tight around here for everyone .
It is not an advance .
It is what I am owed .
Okay .
♪ ♪
( door opens , closes )
I , uh ... I could go to the ATM , but , um ,
it 's a start .
- Thank you . - Mm .
♪ ♪
Mm . Fuck .
( laughing ) : Ow . Ow .
I guess I deserved that .
Hey .
I 'm sorry . I shouldn 't have done that .
I 'm sorry .
Don 't tell Amy about ... that .
She 's a little , uh ... ( sighs )
She 's a little by the book sometimes .
Might complicate things for you .
( elevator beeping )
( takes deep breath )
♪ ♪
MARIATOU : Hello . Assalamu alaikum .
- AISHA : Hello . Mari ? - MARIATOU : Ah , I am just playing .
( Mariatou speaks native language )
Leave a message .
MAN : Head up , head up . Come on . Kick .
Aisha , look .
- MAN : Five , four , three , two , one . - ( whistle blows )
Yeah , good job !
( chatter continues indistinctly )
- ROSE : I got it ! - MAN : Let 's go .
MAN : Ready to go ?
- Everybody ready ? Ready ? - CHILD : Three , two , one !
MAN : Let 's go , guys ! Let 's go .
Keep kicking .
( chatter continues indistinctly )
- CHILD : Got you ! - MAN : Let 's go .
Keep kicking . Keep kicking .
( water burbling )
♪ ♪
( gasps )
( panting )
( water splashing gently )
( trembling breaths )
♪ ♪
( whimpering )
( gasping )
( screams )
( distorted water running )
( gasping )
MAN : Are you okay ?
I 'm fine .
KATHLEEN : Anansi and Mami Wata
are figures of survival and resistance for oppressed people .
( ice clinks in glass )
They challenge the dominant order .
( exhales sharply )
Subverting it through chaos ,
anarchy , creative energy .
They refuse to be ruled
by the human or the divine .
I wish I knew what they wanted from me .
You should be asking what they want for you .
I had to learn the hard way .
They tried to warn me .
But I ignored the signs .
That grief , that guilt ...
lingers with you .
She was beautiful .
Losing her ...
almost broke me .
But ...
I had to forgive myself .
I didn 't fail her .
The system did .
She wasn 't meant to be held down here .
She was meant to fly .
She started threatening to hurt others .
Herself .
A manic episode like I had never seen .
I wasn 't so much scared for myself .
I was scared for Malik .
He was just a small boy then .
I called the police .
Cops didn 't ask any questions .
Didn 't care .
Stormed in with their preconceived notions ,
ready for rage .
Slammed Gloria down like a rabid animal .
Exposed her body .
Handcuffed her .
Started to tase her , so I threw myself between them .
When they took her away in that car ,
in her eyes ... ( scoffs )
( voice echoing , distorting ) : I saw something ...
that had shifted .
The spirits equipped us with resilience .
But the spirits ' tools aren 't always kind .
Some want blood , an eye for an eye .
Some just want you rebirthed so you can persist .
One can never really define good and evil .
My question for you , Aisha :
How do you use your rage ?
Is it your superpower ,
or is it your kryptonite ?
( gasps )
( gasping )
( panting )
( Aisha speaks French )
( sighs )
Manger . Chebu jën .
Yes .
( humming a tune )
Okay .
It 's good ?
ROSE : Mm-hmm .
( footsteps approaching )
AMY : What are you feeding her ?
I didn 't know you were here .
That 's not what I asked you .
I work ...
I work so hard .
So hard .
And the one time I come home sick ,
I find you feeding my daughter food that is way too spicy for her tummy !
What is even in this ?
What if she 's allergic ?
Should I feed her this ?
Hmm ?
Or this ? Or this ?
Since I started , I have been buying her food
or making some of my own .
Did you ever wonder how your child was eating ,
or are you too busy to care ?
Honey ...
I want you to go pick out a book for Mommy to read to you , okay ?
Any country you want .
( speaks French )
Let Mommy and I talk .
It 's okay .
Now that I have your attention ...
My overtime hours .
Did you subtract the hours you spent losing track of my daughter ?
My time is not free .
This is a small community , and nannies talk .
So do mothers .
I am a mother , too .
I thought so .
I knew that from the moment I met you .
It can 't happen again .
It won 't .
I need an overnight from you tomorrow .
- No . - I need to get out of here .
- No . - I need to get away .
I can 't fucking think in this overpriced shoebox .
So , 7 : 00 to 7 : 00 ... 150 flat rate is very reasonable .
250 .
You drive a very hard bargain .
In advance .
( chuckles ) You think cash is just laying around ?
Plus unpaid overtime .
All right . I 'll get money from the ATM .
Adam will pay you in the morning .
( grunts ) It all comes from me anyway .
♪ ♪
ROSE : Aisha , no . Don 't leave . Don 't leave me .
Rose , I 'll be back , okay ?
- ROSE : Aisha , no ! - AISHA : It 's okay .
- ROSE : Please don 't leave me ! - That 's enough .
- I 'll be back . ( speaks French ) - AMY : Come to Mommy .
- Okay ? I 'll be back . - Hey . Come to me , all right ?
You want to go to the dollhouse ?
- ROSE : No . - AMY : Huh ? Come on !
- ROSE : No ! Get off me ! - AMY : Rose !
- ROSE : I don 't want to go . - AMY : Settle down . Settle down .
- ( traffic passing outside ) - ( dogs barking in distance )
♪ ♪
( shuddering breaths )
( hissing )
( yelping )
( panicked whimpering )
( Malik shushing quietly )
Breathe . Breathe .
- I 'm with you , okay ? - ( Aisha breathing heavily )
Ten toes on the floor , okay ?
Say it with me : " Ten toes on the floor . "
- Ten toes on the floor . - Ten toes on the floor . You 're okay .
Okay . Breathe .
Okay , you 're okay . You 're okay .
♪ ♪
( sighs )
( paper rustles )
( alarm whooping outside )
( car horns honking )
- ( traffic passing ) - ( horns honking )
- ( sirens blaring ) - ( fire truck horn blasting )
( cacophony of traffic sounds )
( traffic sounds stop abruptly )
( exhales )
♪ ♪
- ( rumbling ) - ( water dripping )
- ( trembling breaths ) - ( creaking )
( gasping )
( yelps , gasps )
( breathing heavily )
♪ ♪
- ADAM : Hey . That 's enough . - ( Aisha panting )
Come here , Rosie .
Ah , man .
That 's gotten pretty bad .
You see it , right ?
The mold . Yeah . I didn 't realize it was so out of control .
Um , I 'll make up the sofa for you tonight .
It 's actually much more comfortable than that bed , to be honest .
Did , uh ... did Amy happen to mention where she was going ?
No . She didn 't say .
All right . I 'm gonna go .
- I 'll see you tomorrow , okay ? - Okay .
- Bye , Aisha . - Bye .
( speaks French )
Yeah .
ROSE : ♪ La-la , la-la , la-la , la ♪
♪ La-la , la-la , la-la , la-la , la ♪
( Rose yelling playfully )
♪ Sonnez les matines , sonnez les matines ♪
♪ Ding , dang , dong , ding , dang , dong . ♪
( Rose yelling playfully )
♪ ♪
( Rose chattering playfully )
( Rose continues yelling )
ROSE : ♪ Alouette , gentille alouette ... ♪
( Rose 's voice overlapping )
♪ Ding , dang , dong , ding , dang , dong . ♪
( water running )
- Eat . - But I want your food .
No . This is the food your mommy wants you to eat .
Rose .
Please , eat .
- No ! - ( bowl clatters )
Pick it up !
Pick ... it up .
♪ ♪
( water running )
( water burbling )
( water continues running )
Rose !
Rose ?
Please !
We are not playing right now !
( eerie voices speaking indistinctly )
Rose !
( shuddering breaths )
KATHLEEN : He was just a small boy then .
ROSE ( faintly ) : Help me !
( eerie voices moaning )
♪ ♪
( eerie voice gasping )
( voices moaning louder )
( voice screaming )
♪ ♪
( flame roaring )
( voice screaming )
( voices quiet )
( Aisha gasps )
( yelps )
( breath echoing )
♪ ♪
( water burbling )
( yelps )
( gasps )
( gasping )
- ( panting ) - WOMAN ( whispers ) : Aisha .
( gasps )
Aisha .
ROSE : What is it ?
Rose ! Rose !
( panting )
Are you okay ?
( both panting )
Are you okay , Rose ?
I was confused .
He made you do it .
He 's jealous .
Who is jealous ?
Lamine .
What do you know about Lamine ?
Why would you say that ?
Rose .
What do you know about Lamine ?
Why did you say that ?
Anansi told me .
He said it 's my fault .
( line beeps )
MARIATOU : Aisha .
Sorry we keep , uh , missing your call .
Uh ...
my cell , I had to ... ( sighs )
You know , you never ask about me . ( chuckles )
My mother isn 't doing well .
She 's getting worse .
But , anyway , uh ...
I 'll call you back .
Talk soon .
( traffic rumbling in distance )
( cell phone dings )
ADAM ( recorded ) : Took Rosie to breakfast , and I didn 't want to wake you .
Pay 's on the table .
Get that hand checked out .
( " Demba " by Sekouba Diabate and Sekou Oumar Dioubate playing )
Okay . You good , girl .
( song continues playing over earbuds )
AISHA : Is there anything else you need ?
MARIATOU : No . Tickets are booked .
Lamine is napping .
AISHA : Oh , don 't wake him .
Call before you take off .
And how 's your mother ?
MARIATOU : She will be okay .
- Aisha . - AISHA : Yes ?
MARIATOU : Nothing .
See you soon .
( song continues )
( laughing )
( song fades )
Some of the luggage was delayed , so there might be some stragglers ,
but the flight arrived early .
Okay .
But I can 't find my son or my cousin .
Miss , there 's not much else I can do .
Is there any other family ...
( indistinct chatter )
( jet engine rumbling )
( cell phone ringtone playing nearby )
Mari ?
Aisha .
Where is Lamine ?
Aisha , forgive me .
" Forgive you ? " Where is he ?
Wanted to tell you .
Tell me what ? !
You said you would have our ticket sooner .
Where is he ?
None of this would 've happened
had you bought the tickets earlier .
We looked away only for a minute ...
Mariatou !
Where is Lamine ? !
When we went to the beach .
The waves ...
were too strong .
( sobbing )
Didn 't know how to tell you .
He drowned .
We looked everywhere .
( Mariatou sobbing )
( faint distorted chatter and singing )
( waves lapping )
♪ ♪
AISHA : Going to get some air .
- You gonna be okay ? - Mm .
♪ ♪
( door opens )
( door closes )
( " Fully Lost , Fully Found " by Yatta playing )
♪ Falling slowly to the ground ♪
♪ Fully lost and fully found ♪
♪ Running late but almost there ♪
♪ Only stop to check the mirror ♪
♪ Backpack full of things ♪
♪ No one told me what to bring ♪
♪ Teach me how to swim ♪
♪ Make me born again ♪
♪ Ah ... ♪
♪ ♪
( song fades )
( waves lapping )
♪ ♪
- ( gasping ) - MALIK : Aisha .
Okay . It 's okay .
- KATHLEEN : She 's pregnant . Be careful . - MALIK : It 's okay .
It 's okay .
♪ ♪
( " Tunkara " by Sillaba featuring Maher Cissoko and Andreas Unge playing )
( music fades )
( waves lapping )